In today's video, we are going to make a
pumpkin spice gelato in the Ninja
Creamy, actually the Ninja Creamy
Deluxe. We're going to keep the sugar
low. We're going to use alulose. We're
going to stabilize this recipe because
we're keeping the fat really low down to
keep the calories down. So, it's nice
and easy. Let's get on and make it.
Yeah, it's that time. Fall, autumn,
wherever you are. Obviously, I'm English
and we say autumn, but here it's I think
a mix actually. Some people say fall,
some people say autumn. Here, I know in
the US you say fall. I'm happy either
way. Don't really care. Love this
season. It's probably my favorite. The
days are still warm. The nights are nice
and cold. Love it. Anyway, pumpkin spice
is all over the place at this time of
year. What is it? It's a mixture of just
some basic spices really. So we have
cinnamon, ginger, nutmeg, allspice, and
ground cloves. So that's that's what
makes up pumpkin spice. So first thing
we're going to do is make our pumpkin
spice blend. So, for the pumpkin spice,
you're going to need 3 tablebsp of
ground cinnamon, 2 tsp of ground ginger,
2 tsp of nutmeg, 1 and 1/2 tsp of ground
allspice, and 1 and 1/2 tsp of ground
cloves. So, with our pumpkin spice blend
now in there, if you get any lumps of
that ginger, you can just s it, but
we'll likely s it into our mix. But I
find a good shake
Yeah, all those lumps of ginger gone
now. So, there's our pumpkin spice
blend. Let's get all this stuff out the
way. Done. I don't really like ginger as
a flavor, but I quite like it in this.
So, that's our first step. And for the
other ingredients, you are going to need
521 g of 2% milk, 100 g of whipping
cream, 33 36%, alulose, 95 g, skim milk
powder, 31 g, and a cold processed
stabilizer such as gu or zantham 2 g.
I'm doing this semi cold process.
Today's video is pretty simple. I think
you can buy in the US anyway. You can't
buy here pumpkin spice already done. But
for those people, especially in England,
where you can't buy this, that is what
it is. You can get all of this from your
local supermarket, no problems at all.
Let's get everything out and get it all
in our little pan. So, we've got our
milk in there, 521 g. In goes our cream,
which is 100 g.
Our alos, 95 g, and our stabilizer. So,
I'm going to add our stabilizer to our
skim milk powder. Again, if you don't
know why, if you're new to this channel,
you add stabilizers to another powder to
break it up and eliminate potential for
clumping.
It will clump in liquid really easily.
So, and that doesn't matter what
stabilizer you use, it it will all do
the same. If you don't want to use skim
milk powder, you can use inulin. But
obviously, in a 750 g batch, which is
what this is, there's like 30 there
would be 30 g of inulin. So quite a bit
guarant
stabilizer in gelato is higher because
the much lower fat levels and this
actually comes through about 5 1/2 g of
fat. Um so it's it's it's technically
low even for gelato. So just going to
stir that together. That's going to go
in there. And finally we have our
pumpkin spice. You can use as much or as
little as you want. I'm going to go for
a good solid teaspoon in there and see
how I feel when it's warmed up. Now,
this is out here lesserin. This is a
low-fat recipe and technically the water
level is a little bit too high. We're
into I think we're like 70.6%
water and normally my my maximum
allowable amount of water is 68%.
So, what we're going to do is is we're
going to add a little bit of the lesser
thin into the top here. And that is
going to help create a more going to go
for about 1 and a half g. That's going
to help create a bit more of a cohesive
blend of our fats. Um, I should have put
that in with the stabilizer, but there
you go. Thankfully, no lumps.
That's going to give us a more cohesive
blend of our fats and waters to try and
smooth this out. try and make this a
little bit more luxurious on the mouth
feel. That cream is essential to create
that mouth feel. If you remove the
cream, yes, you will remove a good chunk
of calories, but you will also end up
with something that tastes like crap.
So, let's heat this up just to dissolve
all our powders and our sugar. It
shouldn't take a lot, maybe 5 minutes on
the hob. And then we'll come back once
that's done. There we go. Just a just a
few minutes to aid the lesser thin
dispersion.
um it can clump up really badly. So
that's why you kind of should I should
have added it to the sugar, but we got
away with it here. The pumpkin spice,
I'd say that's a good amount or one
teaspoon. So 5 g.
Yeah, I'd say that's a that's a good
amount. Obviously add as much or as
little in as you want. It's it's not
going to affect the recipe at all. So
with that mixed in, we're going to pour
that in there. Couple of things to note
as we're using dry ingredients. So, our
pumpkin spice is it likely will settle
as nearly all dry ingredients will hydro
hydrophobic so they don't uh dissolve.
They they sit there in a matrix within
your liquid. So, I recommend stirring
this periodically, you know, once an
hour or something just to keep that
pumpkin spice evenly dispersed within
your tub. So, this is going to go in the
freezer and I'll come back when it's
ready to do.
And for this gelato, we are going to
take it out the freezer and spin it on a
light ice cream setting cuz the fat is
so low. There's more water than I'd like
in this recipe. So, let's get that light
ice cream setting on. And then we're
just going to dish them up and see what
it looks like.
[Music]
Pumpkin spice gelato. I mean, you know,
gelatoish because it's a ninja creamy
gelato. Has
higher levels of sugar, lower levels of
overrun, traditionally made
commercially. And the lower levels of
overrun are controlled by the spin
speed, so the dasher speed of the batch
freezes. Can't do any of that with home
machines. and even less of that in
ancreami, but doesn't really matter. I
have here some pumpkin spice caramel. If
you want the recipe, it's on Patreon.
Let's get some on the top.
[Music]
I hated pumpkin spice um for years and
something happened last year and I now
don't.
That's kind of how, you know, food
works, isn't it? The older you get, the
more you
whatever.
Obviously, pumpkin spice is quite a
cinnamon heavy flavor, but
you get that cloves come through. Yeah,
it's really, really nice. And the
caramel goes perfectly with this.
Caramel doesn't freeze rock solid, so
it's a really nice one to use for
add-ins. If you're using this recipe in
a churn machine, it's going to turn out
really good. Obviously, you'll get
overrun, which will increase the mouth
feel, better texture, that kind of
thing. Uh, but in an inch creamy, it's
delicious. It's really easy to make as
well. If you're doing the pumpkin spice
or you're making up pumpkin spice at
home, just just, you know, use the
recipe I've given you here and it makes
a good amount and it will last you a
good while. So, thanks very much for
watching. Don't forget to like and
subscribe. I hope you enjoyed this touch
on fall with a pumpkin spice gelato in
the Ninja Creamy. Next week we're going
to do a
low calorie ice cream. And for those
that follow this channel or have done
for a while, I'm not a huge fan of low
calorie ice cream. So, it took a while
to get this one kind of right. So,
hopefully you come along next week and
see how we get on. See you then.
[Music]